<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../sch/dh-guelph.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../sch/dh-guelph.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="resources">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Resources</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt copyOf="../sch/dh-guelph.odd#publicationStmt">
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <divGen xml:id="presentations"/>
         <divGen xml:id="handouts"/>
         
         <listBibl>
            <head>Selections from DHQ special issue on Project Resiliency (forthcoming)</head>
            <bibl xml:id="HolmesJenstadHuculak2023">Holmes, Martin, Janelle Jenstad, and J. Matthew Huculak. <title level="a">Introduction to Special Issue: Project Resiliency in the Digital Humanities</title>. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Holmes_Jenstad_Huculak.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Battershill2023">Battershill, Claire. <title level="a">The Stories We Tell: Project Narratives, Project Endings, and the Affective Value of Collaboration</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Battershill.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Crompton2023">Crompton, Constance. <title level="a"><q>No Boutique or Fashionable Technologies</q>: Project Development, Mentorship, and Sustainability in an Innovation-First World</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Crompton.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Cummings2023">Cummings, James. <title level="a">Academics Retire and Servers Die: Adventures in the Hosting and Storage of Digital Humanities Projects</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Cummings.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Diamond2023">Diamond, Sara. <title level="a">The Dangers of Disappearance, the Opportunities of Recovery</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Diamond.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Thieberger2023">Thieberger, Nick. <title level="a">Doing it for Ourselves: The New Archive Built by and Responsive to the Researcher</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Thieberger.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="Otis2023">Otis, Jessica. <title level="a"><q>Follow the Money?</q>: Funding and Digital Sustainability</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Otis.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="HolmesTakeda2023">Holmes, Martin, and Joey Takeda. <title level="a">From Tamagotchis to Pet Rocks: On Learning to Love Simplicity through the Endings Principles</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Holmes_Takeda.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
            <bibl xml:id="CobleKarlin2023">Coble, Zach, and Jojo Karlin. <title level="a">Reference Rot in the Digital Humanities Literature: An Analysis of Citations Containing Website Links in DHQ</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, forthcoming. <ref target="docs/DHQ_Coble_Karlin.pdf">Preprint</ref></bibl>
         </listBibl>
         
         <listBibl>
            <head>Additional and Supplementary Readings</head>
            <bibl xml:id="Bleier2021"><author>Bleier, Roman</author>. <title level="a">How to Cite this Digital Edition?</title> <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, vol. 15, no. 3, <date>2021</date>. <ptr target="http://www.digitalhumanities.org/dhq/vol/15/3/000561/000561.html"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Broyles2020"><author>Broyles, Paul A.</author> <title level="a">Digital Editions and Version Numbering</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, vol. 14, no. 2, <date>2020</date>. <ptr target="http://www.digitalhumanities.org/dhq/vol/14/2/000455/000455.html"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Carlin2018">Carlin, Claire. <title level="a">Endings: Concluding, Archiving, and Preserving Digital Projects for Long-Term Usability</title>. <title level="j">KULA</title>, vol. 2, no. 1, 2018. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5334/kula.35"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Christen2012"><author>Christen, Kimberly</author>. <title level="a">Does Information Really Want to be Free? Indigenous Knowledge Systems and the Question of Openness</title>. <title level="j">International Journal of Communication</title>, vol. 6, 2012, pp. 2870–2893. <ptr target="https://ijoc.org/index.php/ijoc/article/view/1618"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Czaykowska-Higgins2014">Czaykowska-Higgins, Ewa, Martin Holmes, and Sarah Kell. <title level="a">Using TEI for an Endangered Language Lexical Resource: The Nxaʔamxcín Database-Dictionary Project</title>. <title level="j">Language Documentation &amp; Conservation</title>, vol. 8, 2014, pp. 1–37. <ptr target="http://hdl.handle.net/10125/4604"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Earhart2015">Earhart, Amy. <title level="a">What’s In and What’s Out?</title> <title level="m">Traces of the Old, Uses of the New: The Emergence of Digital Literary Studies</title>, University of Michigan Press, 2015, pp. 62–89. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1353/book.43167"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Flanders2023">Flanders, Julia. <title level="a">Jobs, Roles, and Tools in Digital Humanities</title>. <title level="m">On Making in the Digital Humanities: The Scholarship of Digital Humanities Development in Honour of John Bradley</title>, edited by Julianne Nyhan, Geoffrey Rockwell, Stéfan Sinclair, and Alexandra Ortolja-Baird, UCL Press, 2023, pp. <ref target="https://discovery.ucl.ac.uk/id/eprint/10166341/1/On-making-in-the-digital-humanities.pdf#page=162">148–161</ref>. <ptr target="https://www.uclpress.co.uk/products/211148"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="GoddardSeeman2019">Goddard, Lisa, and Dean Seeman. <title level="a">Negotiating Sustainability: Building Digital Humanities Projects that Last</title>. <title level="m">Doing More Digital Humanities: Open Approaches to Creation, Growth, and Development</title>, edited by Constance Crompton, Richard J. Lane, and Ray Siemens, Routledge, 2019, pp. 38–57. <ptr target="https://dx.doi.org/10.4324/9780429353048-4"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="HolmesTakeda2019">Holmes, Martin, and Joey Takeda. <title level="a">Beyond Validation: Using Programmed Diagnostics to Learn About, Monitor, and Successfully Complete your DH Project</title>. <title level="j">Digital Scholarship in the Humanities</title>, vol. 34, supplement 1, 2019. <ptr target="https://dx.doi.org/10.1093/llc/fqz011"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Pierazzo2019">Pierazzo, Elena. <title level="a">What Future for Digital Scholarly Editions? From Haute Couture to Prêt-à-Porter</title>. <title level="j">International Journal of Digital Humanities</title>, vol. 1, no. 2, July 2019. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s42803-019-00019-3"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="RisamGil2022">Risam, Roopika, and Alex Gil. <title level="a">Introduction: The Questions of Minimal Computing</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, vol. 16, no. 2, 2022. <ptr target="https://digitalhumanities.org/dhq/vol/16/2/000646/000646.html"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Rockwelletal2014">Rockwell, Geoffrey, Shawn Day, Joyce Yu, and Maureen Engel. <title level="a">Burying Dead Projects: Depositing the Globalization Compendium</title>. <title level="j">Digital Humanities Quarterly</title>, vol. 8, no. 2, 2014. <ptr target="https://digitalhumanities.org/dhq/vol/8/2/000179/000179.html"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Stapelfeldt2022">Stapelfeldt, Krista, Sukhvir Khera, Natkeeran Ledchumykanthan, Lara Gomez, Erin Liu, and Sonia Dhaliwal. <title level="a">Strategies for Preserving Digital Scholarship / Humanities Projects</title>. <title level="j">The Code4Lib Journal</title>, no. 53, May 2022. <ptr target="https://journal.code4lib.org/articles/16370"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Warwick2009">Warwick, Claire, et al. <title level="a">Documentation and the Users of Digital Resources in the Humanities</title>. <title level="j">Journal of Documentation</title>, vol. 65, no. 1, Jan. 2009, pp. 33–57. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/00220410910926112"/>.</bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Warwick2022">Warwick, Claire. <title level="a">Interfaces, Ephemera, and Identity: A Study of the Historical Presentation of Digital Humanities Resources</title>. <title level="j">Digital Scholarship in the Humanities</title>, vol. 35, no. 4, Dec. 2022, pp. 944–971. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/llc/fqz081"/></bibl>
            
            <bibl xml:id="Wilson2022">Wilson, Nicola, Claire Battershill, Helena Clarkson, Matthew N. Hannah, Illya Nokhrin, and Elizabeth Wilson Gordon. <title level="a">Digital Critical Archives, Copyright, and Feminist Praxis</title>. <title level="j">Archival Science</title>, vol. 22, no. 3, 2022, pp. 295–317. <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10502-021-09384-x"/></bibl>
            

       
            
            
         </listBibl>
         
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
